[gasps]
[footsteps echoing]
Just stay back.
Don't come any closer.
Pouf, please.
[dramatic music playing]
[scoffs]
[opening theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[singer singing in English]
May I ask why?
If only you had kept quiet,
I would have been able
to kill him quite easily.
Where is all this
irrational fear coming from?
[Neferpitou] He noticed you.
If you had closed in with blood lust,
he would have attacked Komugi.
That much, I'm absolutely sure.
That risk was one I just couldn't take.
but why would he do that?
[Gon] This is none of your business.
You just shut up.
You go see how Knuckle's doing.
Pouf has moved outside the barrier now,
whether to fight or retreat.
[Meleoron] Wait. What about you guys?
[Killua] Once Gon gets like this,
he's not gonna budge for anything.
I might go down with him.
[sighs]
[Killua] I'm kidding!
Look, we're okay.
I've got the magic word "Kite"
as backup. Don't worry.
So just leave it to me.
[Meleoron] Are you sure?
But, if that's the case, then why…
why did you look so sad back there?
You're positive, right?
Can't you tell me?
Don't you want to?
[intense music playing]
[wind blowing]
[Shaiapouf] Ah, I'm downwind.
Farewell.
[Gon] Don't move.
Stay right there.
You use your butterfly wing scales
to control people, right?
Don't move a step.
[dramatic music playing]
Pouf, please stay.
[Shaiapouf] Are you insane?
You want me to stay and do nothing at all,
just for the sake of that girl?
It's for the King.
Please do as he says.
[Shaiapouf] What happened here?
Your attitude is completely different
than it was before.
Something happened
while I was imprisoned.
I give you my word
is that you just fill me in
on all that's happened.
If I ask where the King is,
he'll become suspicious and silence us.
Give me a hint, something subtle.
And of course,
try to make it sound natural.
If you fail, it will be
nothing less than a bloodbath.
That's all there is to it.
[gasps]
[A.P.R.] It is time.
You've accrued interest.
[intense music playing]
If I do it one more time,
I'll have it mastered for sure.
I need rage.
Calmly release my fury,
destruction and creation together…
comprehend the existence
of reciprocal emotions.
And now, in his present state…
[Menthuthuyoupi] Rage like this
should never be allowed to flow freely.
It's meant to be directed, to be used!
[laughs] Another fake?
Well, okay! That's fine with me!
More! More! Fuel my rage!
It is time. You've accrued interest.
assuming that aura consumption
would continue to rise
at the current rate.
Even if Youpi were to reduce
his aura usage
to a bare minimum, in another
three minutes and fifty seconds,
he would lose his Nen abilities.
[Morel panting]
[Morel] Ten left.
[gasps]
It's the 11th hour.
I get the feeling that
he's saving me for last.
If that's the case,
then I'll keep fighting
for as long as I can.
[narrator] Morel had deployed
all of his puppets
within Youpi's sight
in order to keep better track of him,
but there was another reason
for this strategy.
His energy was beginning to wane.
He was so worn out, in fact,
that dispersing them over a wider area
had become completely impossible.
If he lost his focus,
the puppets would turn
to smoke and vanish.
[Morel] It shouldn't be much longer.
He has to run out of Nen
at some point, but…
no matter how hard I try,
my body and soul refuse to move.
Damn it.
[narrator] As he summoned
every last ounce of willpower,
Morel knew his body would
eventually cease to respond.
Unfortunately, this came sooner
than Youpi's bankruptcy.
[panting]
[Menthuthuyoupi] I've got something
I wanna say to you.
[chuckles]
You look like a half-dead fly.
Even so…
you guys are amazing.
[dramatic music playing]
[narrator] He had shown
astonishing growth during combat,
far beyond Morel and the others,
but when he spoke,
it was not to taunt
or gloat over his opponent.
Instead, his words
were of pure admiration.
he expected to hear in this situation,
but Youpi's feelings
were heartfelt and sincere,
a fact that Morel
had no choice but to accept.
[Menthuthuyoupi] I'm not
really sure how to say this,
but because you were so incredible,
I should kill you now.
It's only proper.
Farewell.
[wind blowing]
[groans]
Blood.
What's going on? Did he teleport?
[intense music playing]
[Menthuthuyoupi] I was just about
to cut through him
I figured one of them
had the ability to use teleportation,
but when he vanished,
I didn't see anyone else around.
so if he did teleport,
I wouldn't have drawn any blood.
If I could cut him, why can't I see him?
Does that mean he's invisible?
Is that his ability?
Which means that one of the others
must be able to make himself invisible,
along with the rest of them.
And right before I stabbed
the guy with the sunglasses,
Well, I left a deep wound.
[suspenseful music playing]
The blood. Youpi can see the blood.
We may be invisible,
but we're leaving a trail.
[gasps] I can't hold my breath any longer.
[muffled grunting]
Knuckle?
Why did you show yourself?
The plan was for you to stay hidden
as long as possible.
I'm all done running away and hiding.
I'll take you on.
[wind blowing]
So…
please show them mercy, all right?
[suspenseful music playing]
[narrator] Knuckle took a chance
on using diplomacy instead of violence.
He had heard Youpi's words earlier
and was deeply moved by them.
[chuckles]
You're out of your mind.
That's not even close to a fair trade.
[gasps]
[Menthuthuyoupi] My answer…
is no.
[gasps]
But…
Now those would be terms
I could agree to.
[grunting]
[Morel] No. Don't do it.
Just think. Don't be a fool, Knuckle!
[narrator] Due to the effects
of God's Accomplice,
[gasps]
[Meleoron] Don't do it.
Please, Knuckle, anything but that.
[Morel] Don't worry… about me.
[Meleoron] This battle
will have been for nothing!
[Morel] All we've done till now…
[Meleoron] Think about
everything you've done,
and Morel and Shoot.
You've all risked your lives!
[narrator] If Knuckle
were to stop himself,
That was what Meleoron thought
when he let go of Morel.
Knuckle.
[Meleoron] Knuckle!
[grunts]
[narrator] But his plan backfired.
How stupid.
That's it. It's over.
There's no way
we can beat Youpi anymore.
Why? Damn it.
[narrator] Seeing Morel
covered in blood,
images of Shoot flashed
before Knuckle's eyes,
There. It's done.
A.P.R. is deactivated.
Now the terms are even,
so leave the boss alone.
Nah, screw all that.
[gasps] Wait a minute!
Where the hell are you going?
[Menthuthuyoupi] To the King, of course.
I thought that was obvious.
You want to come along with me?
You'd die, you dummy.
[Menthuthuyoupi]
Then you'd better rush
the guy in sunglasses
to a doctor, quick,
or you just made that trade for nothing.
[dramatic music playing]
[Menthuthuyoupi scoffs]
In a way, this irritation felt different
than his usual rage.
[Menthuthuyoupi] Try me anytime.
We'll fight as equals then.
I don't need to kill you right now.
That's all.
Damn it. I sound like Pouf.
[narrator] During combat,
Youpi had learned
how profound Nen really was.
It had also awakened
his previously meager sense of self.
Once he'd learned
to compartmentalize his rage,
His perception grew.
[Menthuthuyoupi] They're responsible
for the rage I've stored,
so why don't
I feel like using it on them?
I don't understand it.
Now that I have it, I have to use it,
[Knuckle] I lost… completely.
Knuckle!
[Knuckle gasps]
[Meleoron] We gotta help him!
Come on, boss. Let's go.
So go.
You can still fight, the two of you.
Do what you can.
He said to try him anytime,
so go now.
[Knuckle] I can't.
'Cause I…
Knuckle.
[moans]
So why would we keep doing this?
I can't think of a reason.
[Knov] The King.
[shivering]
I'll take care of Morel.
Shoot is also safe.
Do you want to come with me, too?
[Morel] Wait.
Let me hit this little brat hard.
[Knov] I just got word
from the Chairman's messenger.
[shuddering]
He was able to take the King
to the agreed-upon spot.
[all gasp]
[Knov] Even if they leave now,
the Royal Guard won't make it in time,
so consider them fired.
Same goes for you guys. [laughs]
Where's Palm?
[Knuckle] No word yet.
[Knov] I see.
Well, now what?
You're tough.
[Knuckle] Let's go.
[Meleoron] To look for Palm?
[Knuckle] No. We can do that later.
There's something else
we have to do first.
Youpi's not the only Royal Guard,
you know.
[closing theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[upbeat music playing]
[Gon] Next time, "Pose and Name."
Hey, Killua, say my name.
-[Killua] Gon.
-[Gon] Killua.
[Gon and Killua laugh]
[singer singing in Japanese]